Kirito: ENHANCE ARMAMENT!
♪
( yells )
( woman vocalizing )
( Fanatio grunting )
( Kirito grunting )
( yells )
( Fanatio gasping )
♪
Eugeo: KIRITO.
KIRITO!
SAY SOMETHING! KIRITO!
( singing in Japanese )
♪
♪ PROUD OF MYSELF ♪
Eugeo: KIRITO!
COME ON. WAKE UP!
( gasps )
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE LUMINOUS ELEMENT!
( sighs )
SYSTEM CALL.
TRANSFER HUMAN UNIT DURABILITY.
SELF TO LEFT.
DON’T DIE.
- ( hand slaps )
- ( gasps )
Kirito: THAT’S ENOUGH, EUGEO.
I THINK I’LL BE OKAY NOW.
Eugeo: WHOA, TAKE IT EASY!
YOU WERE HURT PRETTY BAD.
YOU MIGHT HAVE INTERNAL WOUNDS
MY HEALING DIDN’T CATCH.
IT’S NOT AS BAD AS WHEN
THOSE GOBLINS BEAT ME DOWN.
ANYWAY, I’M WORRIED ABOUT HER.
Eugeo: WHAT?
WHO CARES?
SHE TRIED TO KILL YOU,
REMEMBER?!
I KNOW WHAT YOU SAID BEFORE,
ABOUT LETTING HATE
GET THE BETTER OF ME.
SHE WAS JUST DOING HER DUTY.
SHE WASN’T FIGHTING FOR REVENGE
OR BECAUSE SHE HATED US.
I GET THAT.
STILL...
THAT’S NO EXCUSE.
I CAN’T FORGIVE THE CHURCH
OR THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS.
THEY HAVE ALL THIS POWER,
BUT THEY’RE
JUST A BUNCH OF HYPOCRITES.
IF THEY REALLY WANTED
TO PROTECT HUMANITY, THEY COULD.
THEY’D RATHER
PROTECT A LIE INSTEAD.
Kirito: I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN,
BUT YOU CAN’T FORGET
THESE KNIGHTS ARE HUMAN, TOO.
THEY GOT THEIR OWN PROBLEMS,
LIKE HOW THIS ONE FELT
FOR HER COMMANDER.
I GOTTA SAY, YOUR PERFECT WEAPON
CONTROL ART’S AWESOME.
THOSE KNIGHTS DIDN’T STAND
A CHANCE AGAINST IT.
THIS FIGHT’S OVER.
THERE’S NO REASON
TO HATE FANATIO
AND THE FOUR WHIRLING BLADES
ANY MORE, SO LET IT GO.
Eugeo: THEY’RE HUMAN.
YEAH, YOU’RE RIGHT.
I UNDERSTOOD THAT MUCH
ABOUT HER DURING THE FIGHT.
SHE FOUGHT WITH HEART, LIKE US.
I GUESS THAT’S WHY
SHE WAS SO POWERFUL.
Kirito: YOU’RE RIGHT ABOUT THAT.
IT’S ALL A MATTER
OF PERSPECTIVE,
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT IT.
THE KNIGHTS
SEE THEMSELVES AS GOOD,
WHILE YOU SEE THEM AS EVIL,
BUT THE REALITY IS
YOU, ME, AND THESE KNIGHTS,
WE’RE ALL HUMAN
AT THE END OF THE DAY,
SO WHO’S TO SAY
WHO’S GOOD AND WHO’S BAD?
( Eugeo sighs )
Kirito: CRAP! ALMOST FORGOT.
Eugeo: EH?
Kirito: COULD YOU GIVE
THOSE TWO KNUCKLEHEADS
SOME OF THAT ANTIDOTE FOR ME?
DON’T FORGET TO SNAP
THEIR DAGGERS BEFORE YOU DO.
OH, AND MAKE SURE THEY’RE
NOT PACKIN’ ANY OTHER TRICKS.
Eugeo: WHAT ABOUT ADMINISTRATOR,
KIRITO?
WILL YOU BE
AS UNDERSTANDING OF HER
AS YOU ARE HER KNIGHTS?
Kirito: HUH?
( gasps )
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE LUMINOUS ELEMENT!
- ( gasps )
- Eugeo: WHAT’S WRONG?!
Kirito: I CAN’T STOP
THE BLEEDING!
HELP ME!
Eugeo: ALL RIGHT.
THIS ISN’T WORKING.
SHE’S LOST WAY TOO MUCH BLOOD.
Kirito: BUT I CAN’T
JUST LET HER DIE LIKE THIS.
SHE’S LIVED A HUNDRED YEARS,
WORRYING, LOVING, SUFFERING!
SHE WAS ALIVE!
I CAN’T LET HER SOUL GET ERASED!
HELP US! THIS KNIGHT’S DYING!
I KNOW THERE’S
MORE OF YOU OUT THERE!
COME ON! ONE OF YOU NEEDS HELP!
CAN ANYONE HEAR ME?!
A PRIEST, A MONK! ANYONE!
SHE’S DYING! HELP HER!
PLEASE, YOU CAN’T LET HER DIE!
THAT’S IT.
Eugeo: WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU’RE DOING?!
YOU’RE SUPPOSED TO USE THAT
ON ADMINISTRATOR!
Kirito: YEAH, I KNOW!
BUT IF I USE IT ON HER,
I CAN SAVE HER.
THIS DAGGER’S HER ONLY HOPE.
I CAN SAVE HER WITH IT.
I HAVE TO USE IT!
♪
Cardinal: GOODNESS GRACIOUS.
YOU REALLY ARE SOMETHING.
Kirito: C-CARDINAL!
SHE NEEDS HELP!
I-I’M SORRY.
I KNOW I SHOULDN’T HAVE--
Cardinal:
I KNOW WHAT’S HAPPENED,
AND, PLEASE, DON’T APOLOGIZE.
I WILL HEAL
FANATIO SYNTHESIS TWO.
HOWEVER, I WILL
HAVE TO BRING HER TO ME,
AS IT WILL TAKE SOME TIME
TO INITIATE A FULL RECOVERY.
( both stammer )
Cardinal: THESE POTIONS
WILL HEAL YOU.
NOW, AS FAR AS I CAN TELL,
ADMINISTRATOR IS NOT YET
IN HER WAKING STATE.
IF YOU CAN MAKE IT TO
THE TOP FLOOR BEFORE SHE WAKES,
YOU CAN STILL ELIMINATE HER
WITHOUT THE USE OF THE DAGGER.
HURRY. ONLY A FEW
INTEGRITY KNIGHTS REMAIN.
Kirito: I KINDA LOST IT THERE.
SORRY.
Eugeo: NO. YOU DON’T
EVER HAVE TO APOLOGIZE.
Kirito: HEY, DID YOU GET THAT?
CARDINAL SAID
SOMETHING WEIRD JUST NOW,
SOMETHING ABOUT
ADMINISTRATOR’S "WAKING STATE."
Eugeo: PERHAPS SHE SPENDS
MOST OF HER TIME SLEEPING.
Kirito: CARDINAL
SAID ADMINISTRATOR
AND SOME OF HER KNIGHTS
HAVE BEEN AROUND
FOR A COUPLE OF CENTURIES,
SO WHO KNOWS WHAT KINDA STRAIN
THAT PUTS ON ’EM?
MAYBE IT’S PART OF THE DEAL,
ADMINISTRATOR HAS TO SLEEP
ALL DAY TO STAY ALIVE.
OH, WELL. I GUESS WE’LL
FIND OUT ONCE WE GET UP THERE.
♪
( both gasp )
Kirito: THE HECK IS THIS?
WATCH OUT! SOMETHING’S COMIN’!
( Eugeo gasps )
Woman: THANK YOU FOR WAITING.
WHICH FLOOR
WOULD YOU LIKE TO VISIT?
Eugeo: "WHICH FLOOR"?
DO YOU MEAN YOU CAN TAKE US
TO ANY OF THE FLOORS ABOVE?
( Kirito sighs )
UM, WE’RE FUGITIVES,
AND WE SORTA, LIKE,
BROKE IN TO THE CATHEDRAL.
ISN’T YOUR ELEVA--
I MEAN, FLOATING THING
OFF LIMITS TO FOLKS LIKE US?
Woman: I’M NOT SURE
WHAT YOU MEAN.
ANYONE WHO WISHES TO USE
THIS PLATFORM MAY DO SO.
MY JOB IS TO MERELY OPERATE IT,
NOTHING MORE.
Kirito: OKAY. WE’LL TAKE YOU UP
ON YOUR OFFER, THEN.
Eugeo: HEY, WAIT!
ARE YOU SURE IT’S SAFE?!
Kirito: OF COURSE!
BESIDES, THERE’S
NO MORE STAIRS TO CLIMB.
Eugeo: YEAH, BUT--
OH, NEVER MIND.
Kirito: ALL RIGHT.
PLEASE TAKE US UP
AS HIGH AS YOU CAN.
Woman: RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE AERIAL ELEMENT.
( Eugeo gasps )
Woman: BURST ELEMENT.
( platform humming )
( Kirito sighs )
SO HAVE YOU BEEN DOING THIS
FOR A WHILE NOW?
Woman:
AS A MATTER OF FACT, I HAVE.
FOR 107 YEARS, ACTUALLY.
Eugeo: 107 YEARS!
AND THIS IS ALL YOU DO,
DAY IN AND DAY OUT?
Woman: NOT QUITE. I GET BREAKS.
I’M ALLOWED TO TAKE ONE AT NOON
TO HAVE MY LUNCH,
AND THEN AT NIGHT
I GET TO SLEEP, SO THERE’S THAT.
Eugeo: THAT’S NOT QUITE
WHAT I MEAN.
Kirito: UM, WHAT’S YOUR NAME?
Woman: MY NAME...
I SEEM TO HAVE FORGOTTEN IT.
HUH. THAT MAKES SENSE.
"OPERATOR" IS ALL
ANYONE CALLS ME ANYMORE.
Eugeo: I THINK WE CAN HELP.
WE, UM...
WE CAME HERE TO BRING DOWN
THE HEAD OF THE CHURCH,
THE ONE WHO FORCED
THIS CALLING ONTO YOU.
Operator: YOU DON’T SAY?
Eugeo: IF THE CHURCH IS GONE,
YOU’LL BE RELEASED
FROM YOUR CALLING.
YOU’LL BE FREE
TO DO WHATEVER YOU WANT.
Operator: IS THAT SO?
I’M AT A LOSS.
I DON’T KNOW ANYTHING
OF THE WORLD OUTSIDE THIS SHAFT.
THEREFORE, I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT NEW CALLING I WOULD CHOOSE.
ALTHOUGH, IF I COULD WISH
FOR ANYTHING ELSE TO DO...
I WISH I COULD FLY
THIS PLATFORM OUTSIDE
AND GO WHEREVER I WANTED.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR PATIENCE.
THIS IS THE 80th FLOOR,
THE CLOUDTOP GARDEN.
Eugeo: I DIDN’T THINK
ANYTHING IN THIS WORLD
COULD BE MORE BORING
THAN MY CALLING,
BUT IT’S NOTHING
COMPARED TO HERS.
I COULD LOOK FORWARD
TO GROWING OLD AND RETIRING.
SHE’S STUCK WITH HERS FOREVER.
Kirito: CARDINAL SAID THAT
EVEN IF YOU STOPPED A PERSON
FROM AGING WITH A SACRED ART,
THERE’S NO WAY
TO STOP THEIR SOUL FROM AGING.
LITTLE BY LITTLE,
THEIR MEMORY CRUMBLES,
AND IN THE END
IT FALLS APART.
THE AXIOM CHURCH
IS STRAIGHT-UP EVIL.
WE’RE THE ONLY ONES
WHO CAN STOP ADMINISTRATOR
AND FREE EVERYONE.
IT’S A START,
BUT THAT’S NOT THE END
OF THIS WORLD’S PROBLEMS.
THE REAL CHALLENGE
IS WHAT COMES AFTER.
Eugeo: I THOUGHT,
AFTER WE DEFEATED ADMINISTRATOR,
CARDINAL WOULD MAKE THINGS
RIGHT AGAIN. WON’T SHE?
Kirito: UH...
SORT OF.
WE CAN TALK ABOUT IT
AFTER WE GET ALICE BACK.
Eugeo: OKAY.
( both grunting )
( stream flowing )
( Kirito gasps )
Eugeo: AMAZING.
( gasps )
♪
( gasps ) A-ALICE.
Alice: PLEASE WAIT.
I WANT TO LET HER
SOAK IN THE SUN.
NOT FOR LONG.
A FEW MORE MOMENTS WILL DO.
( Eugeo sighs )
Kirito: LET ME
DO THE FIGHTING, OKAY?
BE READY WITH THE DAGGER.
THAT’S THE ONLY WAY
YOU’RE GONNA GET HER BACK.
I’LL BLOCK HER STRIKES,
WITH MY BODY
IF IT COMES DOWN TO IT.
Eugeo: BUT CAN’T WE--
Kirito: LOOK,
THERE’S NO OTHER WAY.
I’LL CHARGE ALICE,
TAKE THE HIT, AND PIN HER DOWN.
THEN YOU STICK HER
WITH THE DAGGER! GOT IT?
Eugeo: SORRY.
Kirito: NAH,
DON’T WORRY ABOUT IT.
IF THIS WORKS,
YOU CAN PAY ME BACK LATER.
I CAN’T TELL IF SHE’S
GOT HER SWORD OR NOT.
EH, IT DOESN’T MATTER.
WE’LL GET TO HER
BEFORE SHE CAN FINISH CASTING
HER PERFECT WEAPON CONTROL.
BUT WE GOTTA ATTACK NOW,
’CAUSE THE MORE WE WAIT,
THE MORE TIME
SHE HAS TO CAST IT.
Eugeo: YOU’RE RIGHT.
AND IF SHE DOES
FINISH CASTING IT,
I THINK I CAN USE MINE
TWO MORE TIMES
BEFORE I HAVE TO RESTORE IT.
Kirito: THAT’S OUR BACKUP PLAN.
I CAN ONLY USE MINE
ONE MORE TIME,
AND WE STILL GOTTA DEAL
WITH THE COMMANDER
OF THE KNIGHTS AFTER ALICE.
COME ON. LET’S DO THIS.
Alice: AGAINST ALL ODDS,
YOU TWO HAVE MADE IT
ALL THE WAY UP HERE.
I ANTICIPATED YOUR ESCAPE
FROM THE PRISON,
BUT I DID NOT ANTICIPATE
WHAT HAPPENED NEXT.
ELDRIE SHOULD HAVE CAUGHT YOU,
YET YOU DEFEATED HIM,
THEN DEUSOLBERT.
I HAVE NO IDEA HOW.
AND THEN
YOU DEFEATED FANATIO AS WELL,
AND NOW YOU HAVE SET FOOT HERE.
IT IS SHOCKING.
WHERE DO YOU GET THE POWER
TO OVERCOME SUCH KNIGHTS?
WHY DO YOU WISH
TO DISRUPT THE ORDER HERE?
EXPLAIN YOURSELVES.
VERY WELL.
I WILL GET ANSWERS
WITH MY BLADE.
Kirito: NO WAY.
♪
DAMN IT, HER SWORD!
IT’S ALREADY IN PERFECT CONTROL!
( both grunt )
( chorus vocalizing )
- ( Kirito groans )
- ( Eugeo groans )
♪
( groaning )
Alice: WHY DID YOU
NOT DRAW YOUR SWORDS?
IF YOU WERE MOCKING ME,
KNOW THIS.
I INTENTIONALLY HELD BACK
ON THAT STRIKE JUST NOW
AS A WARNING.
THE NEXT ONE SHALL ELIMINATE
YOUR LIVES ENTIRELY.
FOR THE HONOR OF THE KNIGHTS
YOU’VE DEFEATED,
I INSIST YOU
ATTACK ME IN EARNEST.
( Eugeo grunts )
Eugeo: SYSTEM CALL.
Kirito: PLEASE ACCEPT
OUR HUMBLE APOLOGIES.
WE DIDN’T MEAN
TO DISRESPECT YOU JUST NOW.
MY NAME IS KIRITO.
I’M A SWORDSMAN-IN-TRAINING,
AND I WISH TO DUEL WITH YOU,
LADY ALICE.
Alice: VERY WELL.
LET US SEE
JUST HOW WICKED YOU ARE
BY THE QUALITY
OF YOUR SWORDSMANSHIP.
Kirito: BEFORE WE START THIS UP,
I GOT A QUESTION FOR YOU.
IF THAT TREE WE SAW
JUST NOW’S YOUR SWORD,
THAT MEANS IT’S ITS TRUE FORM.
SO HOW CAN A TREE THAT SMALL
BE SO POWERFUL?
Alice: LONG AGO,
THE SPOT WHERE
THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL STANDS
WAS THE "PLACE OF BEGINNINGS,"
A PLACE WHICH STACIA,
THE GODDESS OF CREATION,
GIFTED TO HUMANITY.
IN THE CENTER OF A TINY VILLAGE,
THERE WAS A BEAUTIFUL SPRING.
ON ITS BANKS, THERE GREW
A SINGLE OSMANTHUS TREE.
THIS WEAPON,
THE OSMANTHUS BLADE,
WAS FORGED FROM IT,
A TREE CREATED
BY THE GODDESS REINCARNATED,
THE OLDEST THING IN EXISTENCE,
A DIVINE WEAPON, INDEED.
EVERLASTING ETERNITY
IS ITS ATTRIBUTE.
A SINGLE PETAL CAN SPLIT STONE
OR TEAR THE GROUND ASUNDER.
Kirito: YOU DON’T SAY.
THAT’S A GREAT SCORE.
IT’S THIS WORLD’S
FIRST INDESTRUCTIBLE OBJECT.
THANKS FOR SHARING!
BUT WE SHOULD
GET BACK TO BUSINESS NOW.
ALL RIGHT,
INTEGRITY KNIGHT ALICE.
IF YOU’RE READY, EN GARDE!
♪
( chorus vocalizing )
( Alice yells )
( Kirito groans )
Alice: YOU ARE THE SECOND PERSON
TO WITHSTAND MY ATTACKS
FOR THIS LONG.
YOUR WILL AND DEDICATION
ARE APPARENT.
THEY BROUGHT YOU THIS FAR.
HOWEVER, THE CHURCH
IS FAR GREATER THAN YOUR WILL,
AND I WILL NOT ALLOW YOU
TO DISTURB THE PEACE
OF THIS REALM ANY LONGER.
FAREWELL, HUMAN.
( chorus vocalizing )
( Alice gasps )
Eugeo: ENHANCE ARMAMENT!
♪
( gasps )
Alice: WELL, NOW,
THAT WAS AMUSING
AND QUITE FUTILE.
MERE ICE
CANNOT WITHSTAND MY FLOWERS.
I SHALL FIGHT YOU NEXT,
SO BE PATIENT,
AND WAIT YOUR TURN.
Kirito: ENHANCE ARMAMENT!
( Alice gasps )
HE WENT FOR MY SWORD.
Kirito: NOW, EUGEO!
( breeze blowing )
( Eugeo gasps )
( wind blowing )
KIRITO?
ALICE?
( gasps )
( yells )
( yells ) NO!
KIRITO!
ALICE!
♪ OH, EVERYTHING
TURNS TO ASH, TO ASH ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ AND EVERYTHING
TURNS TO DUST, TO DUST ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ FORGET-ME-NOT ♪